{
    "id": "1ba32c4bfbaf4b2eb6501fe9b259870f",
    "title": "Relative Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The boy ………………………. sits there is my cousin.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The woman ……………………….. opened the door asked us to leave.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause, we use who to refer to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The police arrested the man ………………………… had stolen the bicycle.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause, we use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We bought some mangoes from …………………………. we extracted the juice.",
            "description": "In relative clauses which is used to refer to inanimate objects. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She was a pretty woman ………………………….. everyone seemed to admire.",
            "description": "Here the relative pronoun is the object of the relative clause hence we use whom. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The man ………………………….. car had been stolen called the police.",
            "description": "In relative clauses whose replaces words like her or his.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "who's",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I know a girl ........................................ father is a sailor.",
            "description": "In relative clauses whose replaces words like her or his.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "who's",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The child …………………………… parents are dead lives in foster care.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is that girl ……………………………… is dancing with Sam?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There I met a man ……………………………. seemed to know everything.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whose",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Uneasy lies the head …………………………………. wears the crown.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "who",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is a singer …………………………… enjoys considerable fan-following all over the world.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}